Practical Applications of the DFSS Methodology
Welcome back to this session on Design for Six Sigma.
Recall that we were looking about
how to take the X and Y measurements and form a simple scatterplot here.
What we’re going to do, is we're looking how to perform tolerancing, or Design for Six Sigma.
What we've done is inserted a line of best fit.
Now, that's a line that you can see pretty much goes through the center of the data.
So, if I draw an envelope around this data,
we can kinda see that that line runs through that envelope.
And what I've done. And we’re going to zero in here.
I'm now going to turn this Y scale around on us here. As we zero in.
We’re going to say for the sake of argument, that the customer
set a lower specification limit on Y here.
And an upper specification limit on Y there.
And a target expectation here.
So, that's the bandwidth that the customer wants.
Now, what I do is come over,
and I'm going to project this line. Now this isn’t precise.
So, statisticians out there don't turn in your grave. I'm going to project, upper to upper
and lower to lower here.
See, as I project over. I’m going to turn it around.
We’re going to zoom back out a little bit here and I'm going to project down.
Just like this. As so.
So, notice the correlation, the lower
element of X goes to the lower element of Y. Upper to upper.
Now, what is this saying? Here comes what's so, so vital.
I would now in engineering this, say this.
That there is the upper specification limit on X.
There is the lower specification limit.
And I project over and down, and there's the target value of X.
So, what that’s saying is this. Now, listen to this. Here’s what’s cool.
If this is the capability through here,
that transfers up and over to the capability here.
See, what I'm doing is reversing it. I'm starting here and projecting down
to the temperature. Remember, X was temperature.
So, this tells me the range in which I must operate,
process, say, process operation 1, process operation 2, process operation 3.
And out comes, here is the product with the circuit board.
If I want that to operate properly here, that solder joint’s gotta be strong enough
to hold up to do that. And this says if that's the pull strength expectation.
Then that's the temperature range I have to hold.
To make that happen.
Well what I'm doing is Designing for Six Sigma.
Because I know this.
If I find a temperature control method or device
that stops it from varying over time,
this little distribution here, is going to get more narrow.
To such an extent,
that I want that to be Six Sigma capable, ± 6σ.
6σ to the right, 6σ to the left.
As that happens guess what? Those 6σ
limits transfers up and over.
That means I get Six Sigma performance out here.
Now, I just reverse the process if I'm Designing for Six Sigma.
I define Six Sigma here and project back and it tells me
where I have to run my process to achieve my goals.
So in essence, as I set my design standards that way, I improve the yields
at each step, which improves the rolled throughput.
And that's what we call Designing for Six Sigma.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.